LUCAS SALAZAR

<u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>GitHub</u> | <u>Web Portfolio</u>

Medellin, Colombia +57 318 3589068 Lucassv07@outlook.com

Career Summary

Professional whose creativity and curiosity describe his behavior. With technical experience as a full stack developer on digital projects related to web e-commerce and user-friendly educational platforms using JavaScript, TypeScript, Node JS, Express, Angular, Java, SQL Databases, and other technologies. Also has practice as a Developer contributing to different kinds of web application. His problem solving, constant learning and communication skills facilitate his continuous improvement.

Summary of Qualifications

Technical Skills:

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Node JS
- **Express**
- React
- Angular
- Java
- Spring Boot
- SASS
- SQL
- HTML
- **CSS**

Career History

EAFIT University, Colombia

Web Development Tutor.

- Proficiency in JavaScript, HTML, CSS.
- Strong grasp of JavaScript fundamentals, concepts, and DOM manipulation.
- Demonstrate ability to troubleshot and debug code.
- Deep understanding of semantic HTML and CSS Styling methodologies.
- Abilities using browser developer tools for debugging and optimizing code.

Globant, Colombia

Sep. 2022 - Jan 2023

GitHub

Apr. 2023 - Jun 2023

Git

Java Developer, Jr.

- Software Development training with EAFIT University's NODO Project.
- Functional Web Application proposal for *financial education* for **Protección S.A.** Accepted as solution by the company.
 - Lead development team.
 - o Backend, security, and endpoints development with Java using the Spring Boot framework.
 - o Responsive Frontend with Angular framework and SASS.
 - Collaborative work and Version Control with GitHub.
 - Database creation and deploy using MS SQL in Azure SQL.

Tools/Technologies: TypeScript, JavaScript, Angular, Java, Spring Boot, JWT, Azure DB (MS SQL), VisualStudio Code, GitHub.

Luxer Studio Project, Argentina

Apr. 2022 - Oct. 2022

FullStack Developer

- Lead the planning and development of a FullStack Web e-commerce.
- Backend structure and development using Node JS with Express framework.
- Frontend layout with HTML, CSS & Bootstrap. Specific areas using React JS.
- Relational Database design and implementation using MySQL and Sequelize ORM.

Tools/Technologies: JavaScript, Node JS, Express, VisualStudio Code, React, GitHub, Express-validator.

Mangueras y Correas de Antioquia S.A.S, Medellin, Colombia

Jan. 2016 – Aug. 2023

Purchasing Manager

• Variety of soft skills including, but not limited to Problem Solving, Communication, Learning Agility, Logical thinking, time management, Version Control.

Tools/Technologies: Microsoft Office, S1ESA Management Software.

Languages

- Spanish (native)
- English (advanced)

Education

EAFIT University , Medellin, Colombia Marketing Specialization	Jan. 2019 – Jun. 2020
EAFIT University , Medellin, Colombia Business Management	Jan. 2014 – Jun. 2018
Complementary Education	
EAFIT University , Medellin, Colombia NODO – Backend Software Development	Feb. 2023 – Apr. 2023
EAFIT University , Medellin, Colombia NODO – Frontend Software Development	Oct. 2022 – Jan. 2023
Digital House , Argentina Full Stack Web Development Course	Mar. 2022 – Oct. 2022